# **Catherine Danilo, LCSW**

104 River Dr.
Titusville, NJ 08560
609-638-9959
Catherine.Danilo@gmail.com

#### **Career Summary**

As a licensed clinical social worker, I provide individual and family therapy to children, adolescents and adults experiencing anxiety, depression, relational problems, adjustment disorders or situational hardships. My treatment approach is reflective and supportive aiming to to uncover behavioral and relational patterns in an effort to heighten awareness and support change. My clinical background is trauma informed blending attachment, cognitive behavioral and mindfulness practices. With specialized training in early childhood mental health, Sensorimotor Psychotherapy, *Mindfulness Based Play-Family Therapy* and Child Parent Psychotherapy, I offer a compassionate and respectful approach that facilitates a greater understanding of yourself, your relationship and your behavior. Through this collaborative approach we build upon client strengths to achieve life satisfaction and obtain goals.

# **Employment Experience**

## **Custody Evaluator Consultant**

Court Conciliation Evaluation Service.

October 2018-Current

- Assessment of the parent-child relationship using clinical observation, interview questions and collateral data.
- Support custody conciliation and compile information as it relates to the parents' skills and abilities to meet the child's needs while prioritizing the child's best interests.
- Complete comprehensive evaluations that are submitted to the court and legal teams.

#### **Clinical Therapist**

Philmont Guidance Center-Doylestown, PA

October 2016- Current

- Assessment, treatment planning and psychiatric referral to center psychiatrists when appropriate.
- Provide individual and family therapy to children, adolescents and adults as appropriate to client need.
- Communicate with team members, family and collateral agencies to support client progress, medication management and mental health.

# **Clinical Supervisor II**

Easter Seals Blake Foundation-Tucson, AZ

June 2015- June 2016

- Interview, hire, train and supervise clinical and non-clinical staff while monitoring quality of work through audits, reviews and regular supervision.
- Oversee clinical services while providing individual and group clinical supervision, ensuring compliance with contractual, regulatory requirements and fidelity to evidence based practice models.
- Coordinate service provision and collaboration with community partners to ensure that staff are providing most appropriate evidence based interventions.
- Facilitate staff meetings to disseminate administrative and clinical information and participate in regular supervision and management meetings to promote adherence to clinical, operational and

personnel policies and procedures.

# **Early Childhood Family Therapist**

Easter Seals Blake Foundation-Tucson, AZ

October 2009-June 2016

- Provide assessment, treatment planning and clinical evaluation as needed for children and families with complex mental health needs as part of a multidisciplinary team.
- Offer individual, dyadic and family therapy services to parents and children birth to 12 years of age while ensuring timely documentation of services.
- Administer psychosocial, standardized, social/emotional and risk assessments in an effort to make diagnosis using DSM and DC0-3R and to provide related case management functions.
- Complete comprehensive parent-child relationship assessments of the parent-child interaction of those most often involved with child protective services and provide testimony in court as required.

#### Mental Health Consultant Liaison

Easter Seals Blake Foundation-Tucson, AZ

March 2012-June 2015

- Provide assistance to the Mental Health Consultant team and preschool manager by monitoring and ensuring compliance with program and contractual requirements.
- Facilitate organizational and community trainings that focus on improving the social emotional climate of the classroom and school.

#### **Mental Health Consultant**

Easter Seals Blake Foundation-Tucson, AZ

March 2010-June 2012

- Provide mental health consultation to teachers and caretakers in the preschool setting that aim to ameliorate challenging behaviors through behavioral strategies, community referrals and psychoeducation.
- Facilitate organizational and community trainings that focus on improving the social emotional climate of the classroom and school.

#### **Mental Health Clinician**

Family Connections-Orange, NJ

June 2007-August 2009

- Provide individual, family and group therapy to children and parents exposed to trauma within Newark preschools and community mental health agency.
- Collaborate with different community and educationally based agencies to identify and provide needed services.
- Conduct and wrote mental status evaluations used for adjudication.

### **In-home Therapist**

Community YMCA-Eatontown, NJ

October 2007- August 2009

• Provide in home therapy to children, adolescents and families from a behavioral and strengths-based approach.

#### Mental Health Clinician/ Case Manager

Project Samaritan Inc. Adult Day Health Clinic. (PSI), Brooklyn, NY

March2007-June 2007

 Facilitate therapeutic and psycho-educational groups for AIDS/ HIV-positive adults with co-occurring disorders in an adult day health clinic and provided strengths based individual therapy using motivational enhancement techniques.

# **Education/Professional Training**

#### Licensing

PA-LCSW- CW019260-2016, NJ-LCSW-44SC05710500

**Arizona State University** 

## **Training**

Child Parent Psychotherapy Training, Mindfulness Based Play-Family Therapy-Advanced Child Development, Sensorimotor Psychotherapy Institute – Level 1 Affect Dysregulation, Survival Defenses and Traumatic Memory, Infant Mental Health Certification

\*\*Approximately 80 hours of additional play therapy trainings

# Internships

- -AHOPE for Children living with HIV/AIDS in Ethiopia, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.
- -Corner House Counseling Center, Princeton, NJ
- -Somerset Educational Services Commission, Bridgewater

# **Education**

Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey

May 2006

MSW- Specialization: Children and Families

May 2001

**BS-Major: Communications and Justice Studies**